mattkrabacher.com

github.com/mkrabacher

linkedin.com/in/mattkrabacher/

# **Personal Summary**

A full-stack web developer and software engineer proficient in JavaScript, C#, and Python with the ability to pick up new technologies quickly. Experienced with various algorithm structures, including numerous sorting techniques, binary search trees, hash tables, etc. as well as the design and implementation of UI and UX systems. Highly motivated, eager and flexible developer that works well in collaborative teams or independently. A goal oriented learner with a drive to effect positive change locally and globally through software engineering and collaboration.

### **Technical Skills**

#### Languages

JavaScript/TypeScript, C#, Python, Ruby

#### **Full Stacks**

.NETCore, MEAN, Python

#### **Front-End**

HTML5, CSS, SCSS/SASS, JQuery, Angular5, AJAX

#### **Back-End**

Node.js, Nginx, AWS, Vim

### **Database**

SQL(MySQL), SQLite, NoSQL(MongoDB)

#### **Frameworks**

Django, Flask, Express.js, Jasmine.js, Bootstrap, Entity

#### **Version Control**

GitHub, Git, Unity Collaborate

#### **Concepts**

MVC, OOP, REST, Agile, Unit/Integration Tests

#### **IDEs**

Visual Studio, Atom

# **Highlighted Projects**

## ForHousing - Demo - https://github.com/BC-Rand/datagov

- Part of winning team of four of the annual 48 hour Coding Dojo nationwide hackathon centered on using Data.gov APIs.
- Responsible for map design, functionality and filtering, that allows users to find nearest free meals and sort by day and meal type.

Technologies: TypeScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Google Maps API, Distance Matrix API, Multiple Data.gov APIs

## Terrorism By Numbers - <a href="https://github.com/mkrabacher/terrorismInfo">https://github.com/mkrabacher/terrorismInfo</a>

- Led team of two to create an app that shows a visual representation of terrorism data since 1970 with Google Maps Heatmap and Charts.js.
- Data provided by The Global Terrorism Database but hosted locally.
   Over 89000 data points which had to be summarized into 1000 point and formatted for the Google Maps Heatmap layer.

Technologies: TypeScript, Node.js, Angular, MongoDB, Express.js, Google Maps API, Charts.js, Studio 3T (MongoDB GUI), AWS

## BivyMaps - Live - https://github.com/mkrabacher/campMaps project

- Acted as lead in team of two to create a web app that displays free user generated camping locations all around the world.
- Users are able to add, edit and delete campsites they created as well as view other users' campsites displayed on an embedded instance of Google Maps with custom icons.

Technologies: Python, Django, MySQL, Google Maps API, JQuery, AJAX, AWS

### SeamSmith - Live - https://github.com/mkrabacher/DanielsDesigins

- o A e-commerce site currently in development in the MEAN stack.
- Users are able to shop for products that have been added by admin users. They can add to their cart and then purchase
- Users can also register and log-in allowing their orders to be tracked over time and for them to edit profile info.

Technologies: TypeScrpt, SASS, MongoDB, Web UI Design, JQuery, REST, Bcrypt, Materialize.js, Express, Angular, Node.j

### **Education**

## Full Stack Web Developer, Certificate of Achievement

Coding Dojo, Seattle, WA (Dec 2017 - Mar 2018)

I spent an estimated 1200 hours of study over three full stacks (MEAN, Python and .Net) to complete each exam (4.5 hours to create a full stack web application from scratch) on the first attempt as well as created a full-scale and deployed project within 5 days for each stack.

Average Exam Scores (out of 10): Python Stack: 9.6; .Net Suite: 9.4; MEAN Stack: 10.0

### **Front End Developer Program**

Free Code Camp, Online (May 2017 – Nov 2017)

An online educational platform that teaches Front and Back End web development. This program taught the basics of web development, including JQuery and Bootstrap.

## **Specific Technologies Courses Completed**

<u>The Complete Sass & SCSS Course: From Beginner to Advanced</u> (Udemy) – 4/2018 <u>Testing Angular 4 (previously Angular 2) Apps with Jasmine</u> (Udemy) – 7/2018 Basics of Scrum, Agile and Project Delivery (Udemy) – 7/2018

# **Professional Experience**

### **Logistics Coordinator**

Northwest Outward Bound School, Redmond, OR, (Apr 2014 – Current)

- Responsible for the organization and delivery of large teams of people to back country settings as well as the maintenance and organization of all equipment at the school.
- Position required a strong capacity for problem solving and communication due to the collaborative nature
  of the position and the work and propensity for unexpected problems to arise.

#### Safari Coordinator

Great Alaska Adventure Lodge, Sterling, AK, (May – Sep. 2013)

- o Coordinated daily safari activities and managed a guide staff of five.
- Maintained records of all safari expenses and activity in state recreation areas.
- Coordinated all bush flights and resupplies to and from our remote bear viewing camp.

#### **Chairman of the Public Relations Committee**

S.I.B. (Dutch United Nations Student Association in English), the Netherlands, Oct. 2011 – Sep. 2012.

- Managed team responsible for the advertisement and public image of the SIB. During my time we held several PR events and coordinated with other committees to facilitate their needs for public relations.
- Responsible for the coordination and documentation of meetings with the PR committee as well as regular communication with the SIB Board of Directors.

# **Quality Assurance Technician**

PlayXpert, Sandpoint, ID, (Oct. 2007 – Sep. 2008)

- Worked with developers on analysis of issues and the direction of our software.
- Tested software for bugs and glitches and would submit bug tickets of all issues found along with reproduction steps.